Maximilian Buchner

Data Scientist/Analyst

- 10365 Berlin,Siegfriedstraße 211
- +49 176 323 499 11
- mxbuchner@yahoo.de
- **C** Landshut (Germany)
- 18-05-1987
- ♠ A, B
- German

- Master of Science
- www.maximilian-buchner.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/maximilian-buchner-426096107/
- https://github.com/SilversunPickup
- S loomdock

Seasoned Advanced Business/Data Analyst with 7+ years of being consistent producer, driven to improve results and exceed goals. Strong abilities to garner team buy-in to organizational changes and drive forward progress on business reorganization. Experienced in Advanced Analytics, Data Science, Marketing, Customer Satisfaction, Product and Sales in Offline and Digital Markets. Fully proficient in SME in FinTech and e-Commerce business.



Experience

07-2020

Head of Business Analytics

SMAVA GmbH

General Hierarchy

- Disciplinary supervisor CMO & Director of Analytics
 (https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-vangeison-4291b138/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/analytics-akash/)
- Professional supervisor CPO & CIO

(https://www.linkedin.com/in/hannes-schroedter/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eckart-vierkant-7846273/)

- Weekly summary of key messages about the business to CEO & CFO /CXO
- (https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-artope-b87/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastian-bielski-4984/)
- Preparing monthly company meeting slides and contributing to investor board meeting slides

Achievement and proofen records

- Merged all analytic and analytic driven employees in one department to streamline data approaches after
 Corona
- Forming a new team of 10 Product, Banking, Marketing and Sales Analysts inside a 14 head strong team
- Estimated impact on Marketing&Conversion flows due to Corona to prepare a healthy strategy and restructuring
- Measured and forecast company budget impact due to Corona and adjusting accordingly to a healthy process

Strategical

- How to mitigate the overall Corona impact and pro-actively find new ways to create revenue according to old budget plans
- Taking over key responsibilities from the Lead position, while building up **2** Team Leads to manage my previous duties
- Identifying real technical and business issues to overcome old habits to generate more revenue, like poorly executed Customer Communication, NLP/OCR readings and Document Queueing

Technical

- Leading a Migration to Snowflake and DataVault to ensure fast OLAP processes under a new DWH structure
- Integrating Tableau PREP and Tableau Machine Learning features with 2019.2 version
- Trying to improve BigData ETL processes from AWS Buckets into DWH and monitor data streams in

splunk with alerts

- Decoupling of Monolith into Microservices and it's impact from OLTP DB into OLAP DWH approach
- RPA processing of complex redundant data flows due to old-fashioned API/REST/SOAP systems

Lead Business/Data Analyst

SMAVA GmbH

Achievement and proofen records

- Meaningful insights across the company departments, mainly Product to achieve a 70% YoY growth and a
 20% conversion boost two years in a row
- Introduced new analytical systems to boost vital business metrics visibility, including the introduction of Advanced Analytics to forecast sales with a **97**% accuracy
- Moving the business from 0% digital share to 60%, increasing the processing speed of customers by 150%
- Interviewing, supervising and motivating 6 to 12 executive members to achieve optimal results on a lean budget
- Solving convenient share-conversion problems with different approaches to optimize ROI towards **10:1** while keeping the CPL stable

Strategical

- Day-to-Day consulting of C-Level to effectively breakdown digital and offline metrics of Marketing, Product and Sales
- Changed a centric BA team to a crossfunctional federated one to cut communication pipelines and fasten the developing speed
- Implementing new workflows, such as Guild Meetings, Agile, Canvas(MVP/MLP) and Lean development to improve the efficiency of the team in the company
- Evaluating diverse organizational systems to identify workflow, communication and resource utilization issues.

Technical

- Mapping of data between source systems and warehouses in PostgreSQL and swarm64 for an Enterprise
 DWH
- Documenting data warehouse architecture to guarantee capacity met current and forecasted needs
- Performed systems and data analysis using variety of computer languages and procedures to avoid inefficient data flows, like by Airflow
- Coordinate troubleshooting support for warehouse personnel
- Validate warehouse data structure, consistency and accuracy by REST and SOAP

Team Lead Data Squad

EuropCar New Mobility Group, Berlin/Barcelona

- Leading a team of 3 employees in a Data Squad of 7 developers in a 250 employee company backed by Europear in 6 countries; defining new mobility
- Responsible for the full data section and constant improvement of Business Intelligence Close working relationship with the DevOps team to ensure maintenance of the Data Infrastructure
- Analytics and roll-out strategies for C-level in the EC New Mobility Group

Time series and live feed dashboards, geospatial data usage, GIS related business development, f orecast models, classification and regression model

Business Intelligence

Presentation and evaluation of reports with modeanalytics, Sisense, Power BI and Google Data Studio

DBA of PostgreSQL, mySQL and BigQuery

Architectural consulting, pruning and improvement of database concepts (monolith and microservicess) to create a faster sustainable business logic

Developing a ETL/ORM software

Merging business data from old age systems (mySQL, MariaDB and postgreSQL) into cloud based technology

• Software Development

Establishing script and software as email crawlers, webscrapers and ETL cronjob processes

ETL administration

05-2016 - 11-2018

11-2018 - 06-2020

Key, Log and incremental data streaming from different sources, such as Adwords, Social Media or CRM tools into Data Warehouses

Compliance of GDPR

Full evaluation and maintenance of a GDPR compliant database

07-2013 - 12-2015

Fleet Assistant

CiteeCar, Germany Berlin

Working Student (on 20h weekly basis)

Operational administration of fleet

Operational related work based on datasets (Excel and pivot related work)

• Strategical development of the business

Optimizing fleet development on GIS interpreted datasets

ক্য

Skills

Tech Stack: SQL (mySQL, Postgres, swarm64, Snowflake, BigQuery ..); Python: ML, ETL, Visualisation, Airflow; JavaScript: (Bootstrap, jQuery, CSS)

<u>Viz&Prep:</u> MS Office/Google, Tableau, Power BI, modeanalytics, stitch, segment, Google Analytics

Additional skills: Google Cloud Technology, AWS Technology, HTML5, multiply functional Coding languages, JIRA/Atlassian Agile Development, CD/CI tools

Business Supportive: Marketing (NPS, Mailchimp, Unbounce, Mixpanel, Adwords, Google Analytics, Optivo,); Operations (Five9, Zendesk, CallOne), FinTech/Banking World (DAC, QES, SWIFT, Instantloan, Schufa, Arvato), SDS and NLP systems for Optic Character Recognition



Languages

- German native speaker
- English native level
- French basic level

얾

Education

10-2014 - 02-2017

• FU Berlin, Geophysics, Astrophysics, Master of Science

Magnetotelluric Investigation of Stratovolcanoes in the Central Andes

10-2009 - 09-2014

FU Berlin, Geology, Geophysics, Bachelor of Science

2D Interpretation of early MT data in the Central Andes



Conferences

TechCrunch Disrupt Berlin 2019

PyConDE & PyData Berlin 2019

Tableau Conference Europe 2019 - Berlin

27. Schmucker-Weidelt-Kolloquium; Breklum

77. Jahrestagung der Deutschen Geophysikalischen Gesellschaft

11-2019

10-2019

06-2019

09-2017

03-2017



Publications

09-2017

03-2017

3-D appraisal of (very) early MT data from the Central Andean Volcanic Arc M. Buchner, C. Kühn, H. Brasse

3-D reinterpretation of early magnetotelluric data in the Central Volcanic Zone in Northern Chile M. Buchner, C. Kühn, H. Brasse